Guide to the Allan Ludwig New England Gravestone Photographs, 1961-1964 MS 369
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Allan Ludwig New England Gravestone photographs
1961-1964
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Ludwig, Allan I.
MS 369
1 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
The collection consists of 408 black and white photographs and 77 slides of New England gravestone carvings. The gravestone carvings date from 1653-1810, these photographs of the carvings were created by Allan Ludwig in 1961-1964.
Biographical / Historical
Ludwig I. Allan, a major force in the field of gravestone studies, is the author of Gravestone Studies: New England Stonecarving and its Symbols, 1650-1815, first published in 1966.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of 408 black and white photographs and 77 slides of New England gravestone carvings. The gravestone carvings date from 1653-1810, these photographs of the carvings were created by Allan Ludwig in 1961-1964. Accompanying the photographs is an index of iconography and a list of New England stone carvers before 1800. States include Rhode Island, Connecticut, and Massachusetts.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mr. Julius Lefkowitz (photographs), December, 1959 Gift of Dr. Floyd Seward Lear (slides), January 1962.
Index Terms
Subjects
Sepulchral monuments; Photography
Document Types
slides (photographs); photographs
Places
Art
- Series I: Photographs, 46668
  - Photograph numbers 1-20, representing years 1653-1681, 46670 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photograph numbers 21-40, representing years 1684-1695, 46671 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Photograph numbers 41-60, representing years 1682-1737, 46672 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photograph numbers 61-80, representing years 1700-1710, 46673 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photograph numbers 81-100, representing years 1692-1771, 46674 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photograph numbers 101-120, representing years 1678-1801, 46675 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photograph numbers 121-140, representing years 1767-1779, 46676 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Photograph numbers 141-160, representing years 1661-1791, 46677 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Photograph numbers 161-180, representing years 1704-1805, 46678 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Photograph numbers 181-200, representing years 1769-1789, 46679 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Photograph numbers 201-220, representing years 1744-1791, 46685 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Photograph numbers 221-240, representing years 1715-1793, 46686 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Photograph numbers 241-260, representing years 1710-1810, 46687 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Photograph numbers 261-280, representing years 1724-1749, 46688 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Photograph numbers 281-300, representing years 1715-1805, 46689 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Photograph numbers 301-320, representing years 1741-1795, 46690 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Photograph numbers 321-340, representing years 1770-1800, 46691 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Photograph numbers 341-360, representing years 1767-1799, 46692 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Photograph numbers 361-380, representing years 1748-1788, 46693 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Photograph numbers 381-408, representing years 1725-1805, 46705 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Series II: Slides, 46669 (Box 2)
- Series III: Indices to images, 46699
  - Identifications of each photograph, in order by number from 1-408. Includes name of deceased, death date, burial place, city, state, size of stone, name of artist to whom carving is attributed, 2009; 46702
  - Index of iconography, in alphabetical order by headings such as Angels, Ark, Dome of Heaven, Fruit, Pillars, Portraits, Serpents, Tree of Life, and others., 46703
  - New England Stonecarvers before 1800, a listing of names of 129 men, birth and death dates, city and state., 46704